Rodrigo Maia

Belo Horizonte, Brazil | +55 (31) 994175953 | rodrigo.maia.pereira@gmail.com aithub.com/rodrimaia | linkedin.com/in/rodrimaia | rodrigomaia.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Frontend/Fullstack Engineer with 12 years of experience with greater proficiency in Javascript and Typescript. Working with React for the last 5 years, I have a strong background in building, testing (TDD) and shipping products from scratch. I am a team player with a strong sense of ownership and passionate about building great products.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Trusted Health

Jan 2022 - Present

- Worked on the team responsible for the onboard and job search experience. Adapted the existing experience to improve the conversion rate taking only data driven decisions. Increased the full funnel conversion rate by 60%.
- Worked on the finance team responsible for supporting the payment and reconciliation of nurses timesheets. Reduced the average time to process a timesheet from 3 days to 1 day.

Frontend Engineer, Fauna Inc

Jan 2020 - Jan 2022

- Member of the team responsible to maintain and implement new features on multiple apps directly used daily by our customers. Using typescript in most projects, also implemented new features on Rails services
- Ran the migration of our biggest project from Javascript to Typescript .Implemented a one-click-deploy strategy using
 github actions and a custom-made Slack bot (also written in typescript) .Pushed for innovation on React apps
 Implemented serverless functions using typescript.

Senior Software Engineer, Decisiv Inc.

Set 2018 - Jan 2020

Working in a fully remote team aimed to develop new features and improvements to the main company product. Mainly
focused on services written with Ruby on Rails and Elixir/Phoenix, also maintaining/creating user interactions with
Angular/React.

Consultant Developer, ThoughtWorks Brazil

Nov 2014 - Set 2018

- ThoughtWorks is a consultancy focusing on software delivery, technical excellence, and social and economic justice. I
 worked on many projects involving agile methodologies and intense client collaboration. Always involved with several
 technologies and high quality delivery. I had opportunities to work with local and remote clients exploring the best
 practices to ensure the best result.
- Also assigned as a product engineer to build a strong solution for internal use across all of Thoughtworks' offices, focusing on building a high-quality product, with technologies such as Ruby on Rails and React, and experimenting with new approaches to agile methodologies.
- Developed several cloud-rst applications using tools docker and Kubernetes.
- For a big flight company built critical systems to provide data synchronization in real-time.
- Developed self-provisioning (using Ansible) applications and implanted Continuous Integration with parallel pipelines.
- Wrote test-first node.js web applications accordingly with the test pyramid methodology.
- Presented workshops about React and ES6

Developer, Ezlike

Nov 2013 - Nov 2014

I was responsible for maintaining and integrating new features to the main product of the company. In a few months, we were able to implant TDD, continuous integration, GIT source control, and asynchronous programming. We are always concerned about the scalability and usability of the application. In less than a year, we have implemented a new architecture that was able to triple its capacity to attend to customers.

Developer and Systems Analyst, webAula S/A

June 2013 - Nov 2013

I was a developer working on the company's innovation team and I was responsible for analyzing and implementing
new features and technologies on its product at the time. I was also responsible for promoting the use of agile
methodology within my team and I have implemented TDD in the company's development process.

Developer and Systems Analyst, Arkhi Consultoria e Treinamento

Jan 2011 - May 2013

- I did work related to software engineering applied to product development and IT consultancies, such as requirements, analysis, programming, tests, implantation, configuration management, and support.
- I have developed BRMS applications using the Jboss Drools Expert platform, having participated in the implementation
 of the rules engine and the creation and use of simple business rules. The project had its response time on the
 alteration and composition of the commissioning structure reduced, ensuring greater flexibility and agility.
- I have worked on the development of projects that used software integration solutions recognized by the market, such
 as WebServices, as well as widespread Java and .NET patterns and frameworks. I have been trained on the
 architectural software principles with a focus on the definition and on the identification of requirements and
 architectural conductors, as well as the usage of the architectural conductors for building the proof of concepts and the
 applications of structural architecture.

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Ruby,

Technologies: React, GraphQL, Node, Docker, TDD

EDUCATION

Technician, Industrial computer science - Centro Federal de Educação tecnológica de Minas Gerais

Dec 2010